Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory02 Mss.B.B61.inventory02
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents B
  - Boas, FRANZ (Box 8)
    - Open letter
      - re Owen Coston, 1940 June 20; 1p
      - re Irene T. Karnit, 1940 June 20; 1p
      - re Dorothy Ofsevit, 1940 June 20; 1p
      - re R.F. Fortune, 1940 Sep. 24; 1p
      - re Amelia Susman, 1940 Sep. 24; 1p
    - Statement, racial superiority, 1940 Oct. 31; 1p
    - Open letter
      - re Paula Jacobs, 1940 Nov. 11; 1p
    - Abstract, Relation bet. Phys. & Ment. Develop. with newspaper clip. & picture, 1940 Nov. 22
    - Open letter
      - re L.M. Macari, 1940 Nov. 25; 1p
    - ?, 1940 Dec. 3; 1p
    - Open letter, 1940 Dec. 5; 1p
    - Open letter
      - re Dusja Trachtenberg, 1940 Dec. 23; 1p
    - Intern. Acad. Sci., Jerusalem, 1940 Dec.; 2p
    - Memo. on Loubat Fund, 1940 Dec.; 1p
    - Open letter
      - re Paul Langevin, 1941 Jan. 5; 1p
      - re M.R. Haas, 1941 Jan. 6; 1p
      - re RC3molo Lachataneré, 1941 Feb. 6; 1p
    - Comments, Liberal Ed. & Democ.
      - enc. FB to T.M. Greene, 1941 Feb. 17
    - Notes, Nat'l Fed. for Constitutional Liberties & NY Conf. for Inalienable Rights--with B. Conal, 1941 Feb. 20
    - Signature on Credo of Teachers Union of NY, 1941 Apr. 14; 1p
    - Open letter, 1941 July 18; 1p
      - co-signed by Louis Bromfield
      - Abraham Flexner
      - Geo. Sarton
      - Preston Slosson
      - Max Weber
    - Public statement, 1941 July 28; 3p
    - ?, 1941 Aug. 25; 2p
    - Open letter, 1941 Sept. 18; 1p
    - Open letter, 1941 Sept. 15; 1p
    - ?, 1941 Sept.; 1p
    - ?, 1941 Oct. 16; 1p
    - ?, 1941 Oct. 17; 1p
    - Open letter
      - enc. list L.C. Dunn co-signed, 1941 Nov. 5; 1p
    - Open letter to, 1941 Nov. 6; 1p
      - Roman Jakobson
      - Geo. Herzog
      - Gene Weltfish
      - Stanley Newman
      - Gordon Marsh
      - Wm. Lipkind
      - Gladys Reichard
      - May Edel
      - Ethel Aginsky
      - Marguerite King
    - Open letter, 1941 Dec. 3; 1p
    - To Germ.-Am. League for Culture, 1941 Dec. 12; 1p
    - ?, 1941 Dec. 21; 3p
    - See American Phil. Soc., grant Agreement, 1941 Dec. 22
    - Open letter, 1941 Dec.; 1p
    - Open letter, 1941 Dec.; 3p
    - ?, 1941 Dec.; 1p
    - Open letter, 1942 Jan. 8; 1p
      - re M.F. Ashley-Montague
      - re Alfred Zahn, 1942 Jan. 29; 1p
    - Draft, 1942 Feb. 5; 1p
    - Address, Nat'l Sci. Council, 1942 Mar. 2; 2p
    - Open letter
      - re Earl Browder, enc. list, 1942 Mar. 12; 1p
      - re R. Robitschek, 1942 Sep. 14; 1p
    - See Am. Phil. Soc. copy of form for grant, 1942 Nov. 30
    - Re Earl Browder, 1942 Dec. 21; 3p
    - Letters of condolence on his death to his son, Ernst P., 1942 Dec.
      - American Ethnol. Soc.
      - Wm. S. Bennett
      - A.A. Berg
      - Frank Bissell
      - A.D. Black
      - John Bridge
      - N.M. Butler
      - Michael M. Davis
      - L.I. Dublin
      - Roger Howson
      - R.P. Lane
      - W.G. Leland
      - B.F. Riess
      - Kurt Rosenfeld
      - B. Sachs
      - Robt. Sager
      - B.J. Stern
    - BF Vita, 1942 Dec.
    - Vita & publications for Biographical Encyclopedia, 1942 Dec.
    - Vita for Who's Who 1942-3, 1942 Dec.
    - Work done since retirement in July 1936, 3p
    - See Am. Ethnol. Soc. Resolution on the death of Franz Boas, 1943 Jan. 20
  - Boas, Harriet B. (Box 8)
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 13; 2p
  - Boas, Helene -- (F.B.'s daughter) (Box 8)
    - From Reiche, Karl, 1915 Feb. 15
  - Boas, M., 1892 Mar. 2 (Box 8)
    - 1887 Oct. 29 & Nov. 11
    - From Boas, 1894 Nov. 16
  - Boas, Julius (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 3; 1p
  - Boas, Mrs. Meyer (Boas, S.B.) (Box 8)
    - From Mason & Hamlin, 1912 Sep. 24
  - Boas, Sophie (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 19
  - Boddy, J.M., 1906 May 4; 2p (Box 8)
    - 1906 May 8
    - From Boas, 1906 May 11
    - From Boas, 1908 May 7; 1p
  - Bode (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1912 July 22; 2p
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 25; 3p
    - To Boas, 1911 June 7; 2p
  - Bodeman, Wilhelm (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 17; 1p
  - Bodman, C.E. (Box 8)
    - From B. Laufer, 1905 Jan. 20
  - Boehm & Wiedermann (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1893 Dec. 30; 1p
  - Boenheim, Felix (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Apr. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Apr. 10; 1p
    - See Kurt Rosenfeld, 1942 Feb. 5
      - co-signer of open letter
  - Boerschmann (Box 8)
    - To Boas, 1912 June 24; 4p
  - Bogaert, E. (Box 8)
    - Open letter enc. with L. Szilard, 1933 June 2
      re displaced scholars
  - Bogen, D.B. (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 8; 2p
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 24; 1p
  - Bogert, M.T. (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1917 Jan. 2
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 20
  - Boggs, R.S. (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 12
  - Bogoras, Sophie (Box 8)
    - From Boas, 1910 Nov. 18
    - To Boas, 1911 Feb. 4
  - Bogoras [Bogoraz], Waldemar G. (Box 8-9)
    - From Boas, 1905 May 25
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 18
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 24
    - From Boas, 1906 May 24
    - From Boas, 1906 June 8
    - From Boas, 1906 Aug. 9
    - From Boas, 1906 Aug. 23
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 1
    - From Boas, 1906 Dec. 4
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 4
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 22
    - From Boas, 1907 Feb. 6
    - From Boas, 1907 Feb. 11
    - From Boas, 1907 Feb. 15
    - From Boas, 1907 Mar. 8
    - From Boas, 1907 Mar. 18, Mar. 22
    - From Boas, 1907 Apr. 2
    - From Boas, 1907 Apr. 15
    - From Boas, 1907 May 6
    - From Boas, 1907 May 21
    - From Boas, 1907 May 23
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 9
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 16
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 23
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 29; 2p
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 30
    - From Boas, 1907 Sep. 17
    - From Boas, 1907 Sep. 18
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 8; 2p
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 15
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 16; 2p
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 22
    - From Boas, 1907 Nov. 7
    - From Boas, 1907 Nov. 20
    - From Boas, 1907 Nov. 27; 2p
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 11
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 13
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 21
    - From Boas, 1908 Jan. 6
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 5
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 31; 2p
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 15
    - From Boas, 1908 May 4
    - From Boas, 1908 May 8
    - From Boas, 1908 June 2
    - From Boas, 1908 June 25
    - From Boas, 1909 Mar. 6
    - From Boas, 1909 Mar. 20
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 7
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 13; 2p
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 19; 2p
    - From Boas, 1909 Apr. 29; 2p
    - From Boas, 1909 May 5; 4p
    - From Boas, 1909 May 6; 2p
    - From Boas, 1909 May 22; 2p
    - From Boas, 1909 May 28; 3p
    - From Boas, 1909 Sep. 27
    - From Boas, 1910 Jan. 5
    - From Boas, 1910 Jan. 7
    - From Boas, 1910 Feb. 3
    - From Boas, 1910 Apr. 27
    - From Boas, 1910 Oct. 12; 2p
    - From Boas, 1911 Aug. 28
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 22
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 26
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 16
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 17
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 2
    - From Boas, 1913 July 24
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 2
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 13; 2p
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 20; 2p
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 28; 2p
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 30
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 15
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 4
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 11
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 17
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 20
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 13
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 20
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 3
    - From Boas, 1914 Mar. 3
    - From Boas, 1914 May 19
    - From Boas, 1921 Dec. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 June 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Dec. 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 29; 2p
    - From Boas, 1925 Nov. 13; 2p
    - From Boas, 1926 Aug. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1926 Nov. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Oct. 31; 2p
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 15; 2p
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 22; 2p
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 24; 2p
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 June 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 June 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1899 Mar. 18; 4p
    - To Boas, 1899 July 9; 3p
    - To Boas, 1899 July 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1899 Aug. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1899 Aug. 19; 4p
    - To Boas, 1900 June 19; 3p
    - To Boas, 1900 July 15; 4p
    - To Boas, 1900 July 25; 4p
    - jointly with W. Jochelson, 1900 Dec. 22; 4p
    - jointly with W. Jochelson, 1901 Jan. 2; 19p
    - To Boas, 1901 Jan. 4
    - enc. Liebes & Co.'s letter, 1901 June 3; 3p
    - To Boas, 1901 June 18; 4p
    - To Boas, 1901 Sep. 11; 18p
    - To Boas, 1903 Mar. 18; 3p
    - To Boas, 1903 June 17; 4p
    - To Boas, 1903 Aug. 24 &July 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Jan. 24
    - To Boas, 1905 June 19
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 10
    - To Boas, 1906 May 27
    - To Boas, 1906 July 22
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 31
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 16
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 12
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 6
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 24
    - To Boas, 1907 Feb. 23 &Feb. 6
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 2
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 12
    - To Boas, 1907 Apr. 20
    - To Boas, 1907 May 25
    - To Boas, 1907 June 13
    - To Boas, 1907 Aug. 14
    - To Boas, 1907 Aug. 20
    - To Boas, 1907 Aug. 30
    - To Boas, 1907 Sep. 8
    - To Boas, 1907 Sep. 28
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 2
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 17
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 25
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 7
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 20
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 25
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 4
    - To Boas, 1908 Feb. 20
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 16
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 18
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 28
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 17
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 20
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1908 May 3
    - To Boas, 1908 May 5
    - To Boas, 1908 May 25; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 June 9
    - To Boas, 1908 June 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1908 June 28
    - To Boas, 1908 Aug. 9
    - To Boas, 1908 Aug. 18
    - To Boas, 1908 Sep. 6
    - To Boas, 1908 Sep. 10
    - To Boas, 1908 Sep. 19
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 8
    - To Boas, 1909 May 3
    - To Boas, 1909 May 9
    - To Boas, 1909 May 18; 2p
    - To Boas, 1909 May 24
    - To Boas, 1909 June 15
    - To Boas, 1909 June 29
    - To Boas, 1909 Aug. 17
    - To Boas, 1909 Sep. 5
    - To Boas, 1909 Sep. 14
    - To Boas, 1909 Dec. 15
    - To Boas, 1910 Jan. 21
    - To Boas, 1910 Mar. 11
    - To Boas, 1910 Sep. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1910 Oct. 7
    - To Boas, 1910 Oct. 25
    - To Boas, 1910 Dec. 12
    - To Boas, 1911 Jan. 1
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 12
    - To Boas, 1911 Apr. 6
    - To Boas, 1911 June 9
    - To Boas, 1911 Sep. 21
    - To Boas, 1911 Oct. 24
    - To Boas, 1912 June 15
    - To Boas, 1912 June 16
    - To Boas, 1912 June 21
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec. 8
    - To Boas, 1913 May 9
    - To Boas, 1913 May 22
    - To Boas, 1913 June 10
    - To Boas, 1913 Sep. 31
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 14
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 17
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 30
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 7
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 10
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 23
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 30
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 14
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 4
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 17
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 19
    - To Boas, 1914 May 10
    - To Boas, 1914 May 24
    - To Boas, 1921 Sep.; 3p
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 17; 4p
    - To Boas, 1923 June 22; 2p
    - To Boas, 1923 July 18; 3p
    - To Boas, 1923 July 28; 2p
    - To Boas, 1923 Oct. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1924 June 8; 2p
    - To Boas, 1924 June; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Nov. 28; 2p
    - To Boas, 1925 Sep. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Sep. 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1926 Dec. 17; 5p
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1927 Oct. 2; 3p
    - To Boas, 1927 Oct. 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1927 Nov. 27; 2p
    - To Boas, 1927??; 2p
    - To Boas, 1928 May 17; 4p
    - To Boas, 1928 Sep. 15; 1p
    - see Duggan, S.P., 1928 Nov. 19
    - see Duggan, S.P., 1928 Nov. 19
    - see Duggan, S.P. to W. Moe, 1928 Nov. 19
    - To Boas, 1929 June 9; 4p
    - To Boas, 1929 June 27; 2p
    - see Boas, F., 1929 July 2
    - To Boas, 1929 Aug. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1929 Sep. 27; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Aug. 20
    - To Boas, 1930 Sep. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 Sep. 6; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 Sep. 16; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 26; 3p
    - enc. to Guggenheim Foundation re Barton, 1931 Feb. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 25
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 30; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 16; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Aug. 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 2; 2p
    - WGB -- to Buxton/, 1901 Jan. 8; 6p
    - WGB -- to J.S. Guggenheim Foundation, 1931 Feb 1; 2p
  - Bogue, Anna (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1934 June 29; 1p
  - Bohannon, C.D. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 25; 2p
  - Bohme, Traugott (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1919 Aug. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Jan. 28; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 July 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 6; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Dec. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1918 Dec. 9; 4p
    - To Boas, 1919 Aug. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1919 Aug. 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1919 Sep. 2; 4p
    - To Boas, 1919 Sep. 8; 3p
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 13; 3p
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 23; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 31; 1p
    - enc. Mex. book list, 1920 July 27; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Sep. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 8; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 July 9; 2p
  - Bohmig, L. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1923 June 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 June 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 July 16; 1p
  - Bohn, Armin (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 1; 1p
      - see FB to Germania president, 1905 Nov. 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 9; 1p
      - see FB to K. Francke, 1905 Nov. 28
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Nov. 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1905 Nov. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 24; 1p
  - Bohn, Frank (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 29
    - Bohn -- to Germ.-Am. league for culture, 1940 Jan. 27; 1p
  - Bohn, William E. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1930 Feb. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 8; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 May 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Sep. 22; 1p
  - Bohr, N. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 3; 1p
    - NB -- to G. Breit enc. with G. Breit to L.C. Dunn, 1935 Feb. 17
  - Boie (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1888 Sep. 4; 3p
  - Boldt, A. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 7; 1p
  - Bolduan, Chas. F. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1932 Dec. 19; 1p
  - Boling, K. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1932 July 20; 2p
  - Bolling, G.M. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1927 Apr. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Apr. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Dec. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 June 13; 1p
      enc. re forming language society
    - see Bloomfield, L., etc., 1924 Jan. 18
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 26; 1p
    - GMB -- from R.G. Kent, 1938 May 13
  - Bollens, John H. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 9; 1p
    - To Boas
      - co-signed by Owen A. Know, 1940 Feb. 6
  - Bollo, L.C. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1919 Sep. 29; 1p
  - Bolte, J. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1923 Dec. 22; 2p
  - Bolton, H. Carrington (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1888 Jan. 31; 1p
  - Bolton, P. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 3
  - Bolton, T.L. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1894 May 23
    - To Boas, 1905 June 28
  - Bolza, Oskar (Box 9)
    - 1916 Dec. 15, 4p
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1896 Mar. 15
    - To Boas, 1896 Sept. 12,Oct. 31
    - To Boas, 1897 Nov. 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1897 Nov. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1897 Dec. 8; 2p
    - To Boas, 1898 July 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1898 July 14; 4p
    - To Boas, 1898 Aug. 6
    - To Boas, 1898 Oct. 7
    - To Boas, 1900 Mar. 8
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 13
    - To Boas, 1915 Mar. 1; 3p
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 June 25
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 23; 7p
    - To Boas, 1920 May 13; 6p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 20; 10p
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1921 Sep. 7; 4p
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 10; 3p
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 7; 4p
    - To Boas, 1927Dec. 16; 6p
    - To Boas, 1928 Feb. 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1928 June 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 July 26
    - To Boas, 1930 Aug. 2
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 June 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 July 19; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 14; 4p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 2; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 22; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 11; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 15; 8p
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 4
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 3; 4p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 1; 2p
  - Bomillas, Y. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1918 Oct. 16; 1p
  - Bonaschi, Alberto C. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1936 June 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 July 3; 1p
  - Bonbright, J.C. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 May 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 11; 1p
    - JCB -- from G. Murphy, 1929 Oct. 16
      enc. R. Likert's study re public opinion
  - Bondy, W. (Box 9)
    - from Parsons, H., 1920 Nov. 11; 1p
      - enc. HP to FB, 1920 Nov. 17
    - to Parsons, H., 1920 Nov. 16; 1p
      - enc. HP to FB, 1920 Nov. 17
  - Bonfield, P.E. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 10
  - Bongs, G.A. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 22; 1p
  - Bonhage, M? (Box 9)
    - To Boas with enc.:, 1935 May 21; 1p
    - To Hoppmann, K. re Burschenschaft, 1935 May 14
    - To Alemannia statement, 1935 May 16; 1p
  - Bonhoeffer (Box 9)
    - To Berlin Univ. Natr. u. Nervenklinik, 1931 Nov. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 30
      - re F. Kallman & enc., 1936 Oct. 26; 1p
  - Bonnerjea, B. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1931 May 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 May 28; 1p
    - To Boas (bibliog. enc.), 1931 May 13; 2p
    - To Boas (bibliog. enc.), 1931 May 15; 1p
    - To Boas (bibliog. enc.), 1931 May 26; 1p
    - To Boas (bibliog. enc.), 1931 May 30; 1p
  - Bonney, J.W. [Bonner?] (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1915 June 11
    - From Boas, 1915 June 13
    - To Boas, 1915 June 17; 2p
    - To Boas, 1915 June 18; 2p
  - Bonnvijea, B. -- [also see Bonnerjea] (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 4; 2p
  - Bookler, M. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1927 May 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 May 6; 2p
  - Boorman, W.R. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1936 May 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 May 2; 1p
  - Booy, T. de (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 4
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 28
  - Booz, Oskar (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1919 Sep. 29; 8p
  - Bopp, V.J. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1914 Aug. 20
    - To Boas, ? Sep. 15
    - To Boas, ? Oct. 5
    - To Mrs. Sophie Boas, 1914 Aug. 25
  - Bopp, W.E. (Box 9)
    - To Boas with enc. of statement of July 9, 1925, 1926 Jan. 15; 1p
  - Bopp, W.F. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1923 Nov. 9; 1p
  - Borah, W.E. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1922 Nov. 24; 2p
    - From Boas, 1928 Mar. 5; 1p
  - Borbolla, D.F. (Box 9)
    See Rubin de la Borbolla D.F.
  - Borchardt, F. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1908 May 22; 3p
    - To Boas, 1908 May 29
  - Borgeson, F.C. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 11; 1p
  - Boring, Edwin G. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1921 Nov. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Oct. 10; 1p
  - Boring, W.A. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 23; 1p
  - Born, Wolfgang (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 June 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 6; 3p
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 30; 1p
    - Also see Roosval, J., 1934 Sep. 18
    - Stix, A., 1934 Sep. 21
    - Minns, E.H., 1934 Sep. 25
    - WB's Life & Publications, 1934 Dec.
  - Borquin, Th. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1887 Sep. 20
  - Boss, Benjamin (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 9; 1p
  - Bossart, A. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Apr. 14; 1p
  - Bosse (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1913 Feb. 3
  - Bostick, J.B. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1936 May 8; 1p
  - Botanical Abstracts (Box 9)
    - only in part, 1920 July; 4p
  - Bou (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1888 Sep. 4; 3p
  - Bouchal, L. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1907 Mar. 6
    - To Boas, 1907 Feb. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 16; 2p
  - Bouchereau, Franck (Box 9)
    - see H.O. McConnell, 1940 Nov. 30
    - co-signed to Haitian Sec'y d'Etat
  - Boudreau, Frank (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 25; 2p
  - Bouglé, C. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1937 May 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 15; 1p
      - co-signers:
        - Fauconnet, P.
        - Gilson, E.
        - Rivaud
        - Blondel, Ch.
        - Rivet
        - Mauss, M.
  - Boulet, A.? (Box 9)
    - To C.M. Barbeau, 1918 May 14; 1p
      - enc. with CMB, 1918 May 17
  - Bourand, Etienne (Box 9)
    - see H.O. McConnell, 1940 Nov. 30
    - co-signed to Haitian Sec. d'Etat
  - Bourke, John G., Capt., USA (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1891 July 5
    - To Boas, 1896 Jan. 8
    - To Boas, 1896 Jan. 25
  - Bourland, Caroline B. (Box 9)
    - see FB's open letter, replies, 1938 Jan.
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 2; 2p
  - Bourne, Joe N. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 26; 4p
  - Bousios, Basil Nicholas H. (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 15; 2p
  - Bousquet, J.H. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec. 4; 1p
  - Bovington, John (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1937 June 26; 1p
  - Bowditch, C.E. -- [also see Bowditch, C.P.] (Box 9)
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 19; 1p
  - Bowditch, Charles P. (Box 9)
    - From Boas, 1899 Sep. 15
    - From Boas, 1899 Sep. 8; 2p
    - From Boas, 1899 Sep. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1900 Feb. 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1900 Nov. 1; 2p
    - From Boas, 1900 Nov. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1902 Jan. 6; 1p
    - FB -- to R.S. Dixon enc. CPB check, 1902 Jan. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1902 Dec. 15; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 17; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 18; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 22; 1p
    - From Boas, 1905 Jan. 3
    - From Boas, 1905 Sep. 19
    - From Boas, 1905 Sep. 21
    - From Boas, 1905 Oct. 25
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 6
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 13
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 25
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 8
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 10
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 28
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 27
    - From Boas, 1906 July 14
    - From Boas, 1906 Sep. 18
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 17
    - From Boas, 1906 Nvv. 1
    - From Boas, 1906 Dec. 5
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 9
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 14
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 28
    - From Boas, 1907 Apr. 1
    - From Boas, 1907 May 2
    - From Boas, 1907 May 31
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 9
    - From Boas, 1908 Feb. 7
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 5
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 4; 2p
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 16